Inventory of the Philip C. McConnell papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Philip C. McConnell papers
1937-1964
62000
Hoover Institution Archives
2 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box (2.9 linear feet)
Diaries, correspondence, notes, reports, brochures, printed matter, maps, and photographs relating to operations of the Arabian American Oil Company in Saudi Arabia and elsewhere in the Middle East, and to Arab customs.
McConnell, Philip C.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1962.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the library catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
American petroleum engineer; vice president, Arabian American Oil Company.
Scope and Content of Collection
Diaries, correspondence, notes, reports, brochures, printed matter, maps, and photographs relating to operations of the Arabian American Oil Company (ARAMCO) in Saudi Arabia and elsewhere in the Middle East, and to Arab customs.
Arabian American Oil Company.; Petroleum industry and trade--Middle East.; Saudi Arabia--Social life and customs.; Engineers.
- Printed matter, 1941-1964 (Box-folder 1: 1-3)
- Photographs, undated (Box-folder 1: 4)
  Scope and Contents note
  Includes photograph of King Ibn Saud by Bob Landry as mentioned in McConnell's journal, 1941 October - 1943 May, found in box 1, folder 7.
- Speeches by James Terry Duce, 1951-1953 (Box-folder 1: 5)
- Journal, 1939 November - 1941 February (Box-folder 1: 6)
- Journal, 1941 October - 1943 May (Box-folder 1: 7)
- Journal, 1944 February - 1954 January (Box-folder 1: 8)
- ARAMCO - Planning Committee minutes, 1943 December - 1944 January (Box-folder 1: 9)
- Memorandum, 1958-1964 (Box-folder 1: 10)
- Reports, 1942-1945 (Box-folder 1: 11)
- "The Short Term Economic Outlook,", 1964 August (Box-folder 1: 12)
- Speeches by others, 1948-1957 (Box-folder 2: 1)
- "Historical Background Based on Interview with Mr. M. E. Lombardi,", undated (Box-folder 2: 2)
- "The ARAMCO Enterprise: A Handbook for American Employees: Introduction and Part I,", 1957 December (Box-folder 2: 3)
- "The ARAMCO Enterprise: A Handbook for American Employees: Parts II and III,", 1957 December (Box-folder 2: 4)
- "The ARAMCO Enterprise: A Handbook for American Employees: Parts IV and V,", 1957 December (Box-folder 2: 5)
- Maps, 1942-1954 (Box-folder 2: 6)
- Miscellaneous notes and correspondence, 1937-1955 (Box-folder 2: 7-8)
- "Graphic Summary: Middle East,", undated (Box-folder 3: 1)
- "Middle East Oil Developments,", 1952 (Box-folder 3: 2)
- Oversize photographs, undated (Box-folder 3: 3-4)
  Contains scenes of the desert and photographs of King Ibn Saud by Bob Landry.
- Posters, undated (Box-folder 3: 5)